http://www.drphil.com/privacy-policy/#california_residents

Last Updated and Effective as of: APRIL 15, 2018
This Privacy Policy applies only to drphil.com (however accessed and/or used, whether via personal computers, mobile devices, or otherwise), or other interactive features accessible or downloadable through drphilcom that are owned or controlled by Peteski Productions, Inc. (“Company,” “we,” “our” or “us”) and that post a link to this Privacy Policy (collectively, the “Web Site”). This Privacy Policy only covers information collected at the Web Site, and does not cover any information collected at any other web site or offline by Company (unless specifically stated). This Privacy Policy describes, among other things, the types of information collected about you when you visit the Web Site; how your information may be used and when it may be disclosed; how you can control the use and disclosure of your information; and how your information is protected.Please read this Privacy Policy carefully. In addition, please review our Terms of Use, which govern your use of the Web Site and any content you submit to the Web Site, and our Video Services Policy, which describes how in some circumstances third parties may have access to information about what videos you have watched on the Web Site.
TABLE OF CONTENTS Privacy Policy Overview Types of Information That May Be Collected
Information You Provide to Us
Information We Collect Automatically on the Website.
Information from Other Sources
Send to a Friend Methods We May Use to Collect Information
Cookies
Web Beacons
Embedded Scripts Do Not Track How We Use the Information Collected With Whom Information May Be Shared
With Your Consent Production Partners and Other Third Parties Providing Services on Our Behalf
Sweepstakes, Contest & Promotions
Co-Branded Partners
Business Transfers
Legal Protection and Law Enforcement
Protection of Our Web Site and Users
Non-Personal Information Third-Party Ad Serving & Audience and Traffic Measurement Services Updating Your Information and Opting Out of Email Communications Social Networking Services Important Notice Regarding Public Areas of the Web Site and User Content Third-Party Content and Links to Other Web Sites Consent to Transfer Protection of Information A Special Note for Parents Concerning Privacy Notification of Changes and Your Acceptance of the Privacy Policy California Residents – Your California Privacy Rights Canadian Residents
Return to Top
PRIVACY POLICY OVERVIEW Please review our full privacy policy below – but here are some key points to know:
We may collect information about you in a variety of ways, including: when you provide information to us directly,automatically as you use the Web Site, and from third-party sources.
We primarily use the information collected from you in order to allow you to participate in the Web Site and to communicate information and offers to you (on the Web Site and elsewhere online). We may share your personal information under certain limited circumstances, such as with vendors providing services to us or for legal compliance. We may also share your personal information with third parties for their direct marketing purposes where you have consented to such sharing. For more details, click here. California residents should also review the "Your California Privacy Rights"section of this policy.
We work with third-party service providers, including CBS Interactive, to serve and analyze advertisements on the Web Site and elsewhere online and to provide us with information regarding use of the Web Site. Analytics providers, ad network providers, ad agencies, advertisers and similar third parties may set and access their own tracking devices (including cookies and web beacons) and they may otherwise collect or have access to information about you and your visits to the Web Site or other online services. Such information may be used to display targeted ads to you. For more information, including opt-out options that may be available to you, please review the “Third-Party Ad Serving & Audience and Traffic Measurement Services” section below.
When you view video content on the Web Site, share information through a social-networking feature on the Web Site, or post to one of the Web Site’s Public Areas, third parties may have access to information on what videos you have watched. For more information, please see our Video Services Policy.
We have adopted commercially reasonable procedures to help protect your information, but please note that no data transmission or storage can be guaranteed to be 100% secure.
TYPES OF INFORMATION THAT MAY BE COLLECTED The following are the types of information we may collect:
Information You Provide to Us We may ask you to provide us with information through the Web Site, including the following:
Personal information, which is information that could reasonably be used to identify you as a specific person, such as your name, e-mail address, cell phone number, and physical address;
Demographic information, such as gender, zip code, information regarding your education or number of children, or similar information; and
Other information about yourself, such as your interests or preferences.
You may also be asked to choose a user name and password in order to identify yourself during future visits to the Web Site. Do not use your real name or the name of any other actual person as your user name.
We may combine non-personal information with personal information, in which case we will treat the combined information as personal information under this Privacy Policy.
Providing us with information about yourself is your choice, and you can always choose not to provide certain information, but then you may not be able to take advantage of some of the Web Site’s features.
Note that we may de-identify personal information we have received, turning it into non-personal information. This is sometimes accomplished using a mathematical process (commonly known as a hash function) to convert information into a code. The code does not identify you directly, but it may be used to connect your activity and interests.
Information We Collect Automatically on the Web Site
We may collect information automatically when you visit the Web Site, including:
Information about your device, including device type and settings, and browser type and operating system;
Web sites or other services you visited before and after visiting the Web Site;
Areas of the Web Site with which you interact, advertisements you view, and links you click on within the Web Site;
Your Internet Protocol (IP) address, which is a number automatically assigned to your device whenever you access the Internet, or another unique identifier for the device you use to access the Web Site (e.g. Apple’s Identifier for Advertising (IDFA) or Google’s Android Advertising ID (AAID)). IP address can sometimes be used to derive your general geographic area.
Information about your internet connection (e.g., mobile operator, ISP, WiFi connection).
Information collected through cookies, web beacons, and other similar technologies.
Information about your interactions with email messages, such as the links clicked on and whether the messages were opened or forwarded.
When analyzed, this usage information helps us determine how visitors arrive at the Web Site, what type of content is most popular, what type of content you may find most relevant and what type of visitors are interested in particular kinds of content and advertising.
Information from Other Sources We may receive information about you from other sources. For example, we may obtain geographic or demographic information, or information regarding your possible interests, from third parties, or we may receive information from a marketing partner in connection with a co-branded web site or promotion. We may use this information for a variety of purposes, including to enhance our ability to serve you and to tailor content and ads we serve to you. We may combine the information we receive from those other sources with information we collect through the Web Site. In those cases, we will apply this Privacy Policy to any personal information received, unless otherwise specifically disclosed by us at the time you provide your personal information
Send to a Friend If you send a friend a communication from the Web Site, the information you provide (names, e-mail addresses, phone numbers, etc.) is used on a one-time basis to facilitate the communication and is not used for any other marketing purpose, unless we obtain additional consent from that person.
Return to Top
METHODS WE MAY USE TO COLLECT INFORMATION
Cookies The Web Site uses standard technology called “cookies,” which are small data files that are transferred to your device when you visit the Web Site, if your browser is set to accept cookies. Cookies automatically identify your web browser to the Web Site whenever you visit the Web Site, and may make navigating and using the Web Site easier for you and allow you to personalize your experience on the Web Site. If you do not want to allow information to be collected through the use of cookies, you can generally opt out of providing this information by setting your browser to reject cookies. However, please be aware that some areas of the Web Site may not provide you with an acceptable user experience if you have disabled the use of cookies.
Web Beacons The Web Site and any communications sent by the Web Site may contain electronic images (generally, single-pixel “.gif” images) called “web beacons.” These web beacons allow Company and third parties to monitor and collect certain information about the viewer of the web page, web-based document, e-mail message, or other communication, such as the type of browser requesting the web beacon, a unique identifier of the device that the web beacon is sent to and the time the web beacon was viewed.
Embedded Scripts
An embedded script is programming code that is designed to collect information about your interactions with the Web Site, such as the links you click on. The code is temporarily downloaded onto your device from our server or a third-party service provider, is active only while you are connected to the Web Site, and is deactivated or deleted thereafter.
In addition, we may use a variety of other technologies that collect similar information for security and fraud detection purposes.
Return to Top
DO NOT TRACK Some Internet browsers include the ability to transmit “Do Not Track” signals. Since uniform standards for “Do Not Track” signals have not been adopted, this Web Site does not process or respond to “Do Not Track” signals. To learn more about “Do Not Track,” please visit “All About Do Not Track” at www.allaboutdnt.com/.
Return to Top
HOW WE USE THE INFORMATION COLLECTED The information we collect may be used to:
Provide you with electronic newsletters, information, special offers and promotional materials on behalf of us or third parties;
Fulfill your requests for products, services, and information and complete a transaction that you have requested;
>
Enable you to participate in Web Site features, such as surveys, polls, sweepstakes/contests, and Public Areas (defined below);
Contact you about the Web Site, including, without limitation, in our discretion to notify you of changes to this Privacy Policy, the Web Site’s Terms of Use, or other policies that affect your use of the Web Site;
Analyze the use of Web Site and information about visitors to our Web Site to understand and improve our service offerings and for other internal business purposes;
Customize the advertising and content you see, both on the Web Site and elsewhere online;
Comply with and monitor compliance with our Terms of Use and other applicable agreements and polices;
Evaluate you for a possible invitation to be a guest on the Dr. Phil Show;
Generate topics for the Dr. Phil Show;
Determine whether we may offer you a reservation to be an audience member at the Dr. Phil Show; and
For other purposes disclosed when you provide your information.
Please note that information submitted to the Web Site via an “Ask Contact Us,”Send Your Comments," or other similar mechanism will not necessarily receive a response. We will not use any such information you provide for marketing purposes unrelated to your request, although we may contact you regarding your submission or being a guest on the Dr. Phil Show.
Return to Top
WITH WHOM INFORMATION MAY BE SHARED We may share information collected about you as disclosed at the time of collection, as otherwise disclosed in this privacy policy, and in the following circumstances:
With your Consent
With your consent, we may share your personal information with third-party marketing partners for their own marketing purposes. We do not share your personal information with third parties for those third parties’ marketing purposes unless you opt-in to such sharing at the time you provide your personal information. If you do agree to have your personal information shared, your personal information will be disclosed to such third party(s) and all information you disclose will be subject to the privacy policy and practices of such third party(s). We are not responsible for the privacy policies and practices of such third party(s) and, therefore, you should review the privacy policies and practices of such third party(s) prior to agreeing to receive such information from third party(s). If you later decide that you no longer want to receive communication from a third party, you will need to contact that third party directly
Production partners and other third parties providing services on our behalf We may share personal information with production partners and other third parties performing functions on our behalf; examples include vetting potential guests for the Dr. Phil Show, hosting or operating the Web Site, sending e-mail and/or other communications, providing wireless services, removing repetitive information from customer lists, data analysis, marketing assistance, and customer service. These third parties may have access to your personal information for the purpose of performing such functions on our behalf.
Sweepstakes, Contests and Promotions When you choose to enter a sweepstakes, contest, or other promotion, and in accordance with the terms and conditions of the promotion, your information may be disclosed to our sponsors and third parties who help design, administer and implement the promotion, including in connection with winner selection, prize fulfillment and aggregated data analysis. Your information also may be disclosed as required by law, such as on a winners list. Also, by entering a promotion, you are agreeing to the official rules that govern that promotion, which may contain specific requirements of you, including, except where prohibited by law, allowing the sponsor(s) of the promotion to use your name, voice and/or likeness in advertising or marketing associated with the promotion.
Business Transfers We may share your information, including personal information, in connection with a substantial corporate transaction, such as the sale of Web Site or Company, a merger, consolidation, asset sale, or in the unlikely event of bankruptcy, and including any due diligence process.
Co-Branded Partners Co-Branded Partners are third parties with whom we may jointly offer a service or feature. You can tell when you are accessing a service or feature offered by a Co-Branded Partner because the Co-Branded Partner's name will be featured prominently. You may be asked to provide information about yourself to register for a service offered by a Co-Branded Partner. In doing so, you may be providing your information to both us and the Co-Branded Partner, or we may share your information with the Co-Branded Partner. Please note that the Co-Branded Partner's privacy policy may also apply to its use of your information.
Legal Protections and Law Enforcement We may disclose information about our users, including personal information, to respond to subpoenas, court orders, legal process, and other law enforcement measures (e.g., at the request of governmental authorities conducting an investigation); and to comply with other legal obligations. We may also use device identifiers to identify users, and may do so in cooperation with copyright owners, internet service providers, wireless service providers or law enforcement agencies in our discretion. Such disclosures may be carried out without notice to you.
Protection of Our Web Site and Users
We may disclose information to protect and defend the legal rights, interests, and safety of us and our partners and their employees, agents, and contractors (including enforcing our agreements), and to protect the safety and security of users of the Web Site and members of the public.
Non-Personal Information We may share non-personal information, such as aggregate user statistics, demographic information, and web site usage information with third parties in our discretion.
Return to Top
THIRD-PARTY AD SERVING & AUDIENCE AND TRAFFIC MEASUREMENT SERVICES
The Web Site works with network advertisers, ad agencies, analytics service providers, and other third parties to serve third-party advertisements on the Web Site, to serve our advertisements elsewhere online, and to provide us with information regarding use of and traffic on the Web Site (including without limitation the pages viewed and the actions users take when visiting the Web Site) and the effectiveness of our advertisements. The advertisements you see may be served by one or more third parties, who may use information about your activities on the Web Site, and other web sites and services you visit, over time and across the various devices you use, to provide you targeted advertising based upon your interests. One of the third parties with whom we work is CBS Interactive, which is primarily responsible for the advertising on the Web Site. You can review CBS Interactive’s privacy policy at www.cbsinteractive.com/legal/cbsi/privacy-policy.
Our service providers may collect certain information about your visits to and activity on the Web Site and other websites and services and may use this information to target advertising to you. These third parties may collect information through their own cookies, web beacons, and other similar technologies, and may otherwise collect or have access to information about you (such as usage information and device identifier), in an effort to understand your interests and deliver advertisements that are tailored to your interests. Some of these parties may collect personal information over time when you visit the Web Site or other online websites and services
Cookies and web beacons, including without limitation those set by third-party network advertisers, may be used to (among other things): target advertisements, prevent you from seeing the same advertisements too many times, and conduct research regarding the usefulness of certain advertisements to you.
We do not have access to the information these third parties may collect about your interests to deliver relevant advertising to you, and the information practices of these third parties are not covered by this Privacy Policy. However, as described elsewhere in this Privacy Policy, we may share certain non-personal information such as device identifiers, usage information and other de-identified information, including sharing with our third-party advertising companies, analytics providers and other vendors for advertising and analytics purposes.
We use a variety of service providers to perform advertising and analytics services. Some of these companies may offer you a way to choose not to have your information used for advertising purposes.
You may learn more about opting out of certain information use practices by CBS Interactive by visiting www.cbsinteractive.com/legal/cbsi/privacy-policy/business-partner-ad-opt-out.
In addition, some of these companies are members of the Network Advertising Initiative (“NAI”), which offers a single location to opt out of receiving tailored ads from member companies. To opt out of information collection by NAI member companies, or to obtain information about the technologies they use or their own privacy policies, please visit the NAI consumer opt out page.
Also, through the Digital Advertising Alliance (“DAA”), several media and marketing associations have developed an industry self-regulatory program to give consumers a better understanding of and greater control over ads that are customized based on their online behavior across different Web Sites. To learn more and make choices about interest-based ads from participating third parties, please visit the DAA consumer opt out page.
We use Google Analytics, which uses cookies and similar technologies to collect and analyze information about use of the Web Site and report on activities and trends. This service may also collect information regarding the use of other websites, apps, and online resources. You can learn about Google’s practices by going to www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/, and opt out of them by downloading the Google Analytics opt-out browser add-on, available at https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout.
Third-party market research services, such as Nielsen, may access information about you through your social networking services. You can prevent Nielsen from receiving any data from Facebook that includes information identifying you by opting out of Nielsen measurement. Please click here to read about Facebook’s participation in Nielsen’s measurement services. Please click here for more information about Nielsen digital measurement products and here to learn how to opt out of Nielsen measurement services.
If you opt out of having your information used to deliver advertisements tailored to your interests, you will continue to see advertisements on our Web Site, but these advertisements may not be as relevant to you. These online advertising efforts on the Web Site do not result in you seeing more advertisements, just more relevant advertising, and they allow us to provide you with free content and services. We hope you value our efforts to show you content and advertising that more closely reflects your interests.
Some of these advertising and analytics providers may, through the use of cookies, web beacons, and similar technologies on the Web Site, have access to information about the content viewed by Web Site users – including video content. For more information, please see our Video Services Policy.
Return to Top
UPDATING YOUR INFORMATION AND OPTING OUT OF EMAIL COMMUNICATIONS The Web Site may contain web pages through which you can correct or update some of the personal information you have provided to us through registration with the Web Site or through which you may be able to unsubscribe from or modify the marketing emails or similar communications from the Web Site. We will make good faith efforts to make requested changes in our active databases as soon as reasonably practicable. If you have made any public posting, such as in a Public Area, these communications generally will not be removed. With regard to marketing emails and similar communications you may receive from us, you may tell us you no longer want to receive these emails from the Web Site by following the opt-out instructions provided to you in those communications. Please note that we reserve the right to send you certain communications relating to your account or use of the Web Site, such as administrative and services announcements and these transactional account messages may be unaffected if you choose to opt-out from marketing communications.
Return to Top
SOCIAL NETWORKING SERVICES
We may offer you the ability to use certain third-party social networking services through the Web Site. For example, you can use third-party social networking services, such as Facebook or Twitter, to share information about your experience on the Web Site with your friends and followers on those services. These social networking services may be able to collect information about you, including about your activities on the Web Site, and they also may notify your friends on their services that you are a Web Site user or about your use of the Web Site, in accordance with their own privacy policies.By using third-party social networking services through the Web Site, you consent to share information about you, including video content that you have watched on the Web Site, with your friends and followers on those services. (Please see our Video Services Policy for more information on sharing of video content information with social networking services.) You may be able to limit how a third-party social networking service shares your information by visiting your social networking service’s website and updating your privacy settings.
IMPORTANT NOTICE REGARDING PUBLIC AREAS OF THE WEB SITE AND USER CONTENT
The Web Site may provide features that allow or enable you to create a public profile which may include information such as your photo, name, contact information, and other information that you choose to post publicly ("Profile").
The Web Site may contain public areas to which you can contribute your original text and audio or video content, such as comments, message boards, blog comments areas, personal blogs, online chat features, and any public portion of your Profile (collectively, "Public Areas"). If you submit comments, message board posts, votes, reviews, suggestions, chat messages, photographs, videos, audio recordings, music, text or other content ("User Content") to Public Areas, it may be published online or offline in any media or format (currently existing or later developed). Note that comment and review features, as well as other Public Areas, may be offered and controlled by third parties. Other users of the Web Site will have access to your User Content that is posted on the Web Site and may have the ability to share it with third parties across the Internet, including through the use of Web Site features allowing users to share links to User Content with third party web sites (such as Facebook, Twitter and similar sites). Company may use your User Content, or any portion of your User Content, that you submit to be published on the Web Site, whether directly to us or through a third party, for advertising, marketing, publicity and promotional activities. For the full terms and conditions regarding User Content you submit to the Web Site, please review the Web Site's Terms of Use.
If you submit any User Content to Company or to a third party offering features on the Web Site, that User Content may be published online or offline (including, without limitation, on the Dr. Phil television show how, on a CD or DVD, or any other electronic or non-electronic media or format currently existing or later developed), we and our service providers, as well as any third party to whom you submit the User Content, may publish your name, voice, likeness and other personal information in connection with publishing the User Content or any portion thereof, and may use the User Content and any excerpt thereof in connection with advertising, marketing, publicity and promotional activities. For the full terms and conditions regarding User Content, please review the Web Site's Terms of Use.
You also may have the ability to interact and communicate other members on the Web Site. Please use caution when interacting and communicating with people that you do not know personally. Please note that Company cannot ensure the security of any information you choose to make public and cannot ensure that parties who have access to such publicly available information will respect your privacy. Therefore, use caution when including personal information in User Content or a Public Area or any message that you send using the Web Site or electing to personal information in your Profile viewable to other members.
THIRD-PARTY CONTENT AND LINKS TO OTHER WEB SITES Certain content on the Web Site (such as advertisements) may be hosted and served by third parties. In addition, please note that the Web Site may contain links to other websites and services. We are not responsible for the privacy practices of those websites, and we recommend that you review the privacy policies of each website that you visit. When you select a link to a third-party web site from our Web Site (e.g., if you click through a banner advertisement), you will be leaving the Web Site. Any information that you disclose on the third-party website will be governed by that website's privacy policy
Return to Top
CONSENT TO TRANSFER
The Web Site is operated in the United States and we do not intend to collect Personal Information from users residing outside the United States or Canada. If you are located outside of the United States (including, without limitation, within the European Union), please be aware that information we collect will be transferred to and processed in the United States. By using the Web Site or providing us with any information, you consent to the transfer, processing and storage of your information in the United States, a jurisdiction in which the privacy laws may not be as comprehensive as those in the country where you reside and/or are a citizen, and you agree that the laws of the United States and the State of California will apply.
Return to Top
PROTECTION OF INFORMATION We have adopted commercially reasonable technical, administrative, and physical procedures to help protect your information from loss, misuse, unauthorized access, and alteration. Please note that no data transmission or storage can be guaranteed to be 100% secure and we cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us.
Return to Top
A SPECIAL NOTE FOR PARENTS CONCERNING PRIVACY The Web Site is a general audience web site. We do not knowingly collect any personal information from children younger than the age of thirteen (13) on the Web Site and we will delete any information later determined to be from a user younger than thirteen (13).
Return to Top
NOTIFICATION OF CHANGES AND YOUR ACCEPTANCE OF THE PRIVACY POLICY By using the Web Site, you acknowledge your agreement to the terms of this Privacy Policy. From time to time, Company may update this Privacy Policy. However, Company will use your personal information in a manner consistent with the Privacy Policy in effect at the time you submitted the information, unless you consent to the new or revised policy.<
Return to Top
CALIFORNIA RESIDENTS – YOUR CALIFORNIA PRIVACY RIGHTS Pursuant to California Civil Code Section 1798.83, residents of the State of California have the right to request certain information from companies conducting business in California relating to third parties to which the company has disclosed certain categories of personal information during the preceding year for the third parties’ direct marketing purposes. Alternatively, the law provides that a company may comply, as we do, by disclosing in its privacy policy that it provides consumers a choice (opt-out or opt-in) regarding sharing personal information with third parties for those third parties’ direct marketing purposes, and information on how to exercise that choice. As stated above in this Privacy Policy, Company provides you a choice prior to sharing your personal information with third parties for their direct marketing purposes. If you do not opt-in at the time Company offers that choice, Company does not share your information with that identified third party for its direct marketing purposes.
If you are a California resident and you have questions about our practices with respect to sharing information with third parties for their direct marketing purposes and your ability to exercise choice, please send your request by email to drphil-legal@drphil.com or write to us at
Peteski Productions, Inc., Attn: Legal, 2450 Colorado Avenue, Suite #500E, Santa Monica, CA 90404-3443. You must put the statement “Your California Privacy Rights” in the subject field of your e-mail or include it in your writing if you choose to write to us at the designated mailing address. You must include your name, street address, city, state, and ZIP code. We are not responsible for notices that are not labeled or sent properly, or do not have complete information.
California Consumer Protection Act (“CCPA”)
The California Consumer Privacy Act (CCPA) provides consumers who are residents of the State of California with specific rights related to their personal information, subject to certain exceptions.  It also requires us to disclose the information we collect, the purposes for which we collect it, and what we share and disclose.
The Personal Information We Collect and Why
You have the right to know what personal information we collect and why. The information we collect and the purposes for which we use it are described in this Privacy Policy
The Personal Information We Share or Disclose
You have the right to know what personal information we disclose or share with third parties.  The personal information we share is described in this Privacy Policy
Right to Know
You have the right to ask us what personal information we have collected from you over the past 12 months.  You may make such requests up to twice a year.
Right to Delete
You have the right to ask us to delete your personal information.  In certain circumstances the law may not require or permit us to delete certain personal information, but if we cannot honor a deletion request, we will tell you.
Right to Opt-Out (“Do Not Sell”)
You have the right to tell us not to disclose or transfer your personal information to a third party in exchange for something of value.  The CCPA refers to this as your right to say “Do Not Sell” my personal information.  If you opt out of disclosure or transfer of your personal information, you may later opt-in again to having your personal information move more freely.
13-15 Year Olds
We automatically opt-out consumers whom we actually know are at least 13 and less than 16 years old.  In the language of the CCPA, we “do not sell” their personal information unless they opt-in.
Exercising Your Rights
Right to Know and Right to Delete
You may ask us for the personal information we have about you, or ask us to delete your personal information, by emailing us at privacy@drphil.com or by calling 800.549.7529.  When you make a request online, we will verify your identity by sending you an email and asking you to respond. When you call the toll-free number, you must leave a name and address or email address we can use to contact you.
If you ask what personal information we have received from you, and we cannot verify your identity, or if providing the information you have requested creates a security risk, we will give you a general description of the type of personal information we have about you.
If you ask us to delete your personal information, and we can’t verify your identity and confirm that you made the request, we will not be able to honor it.  Generally, though, if we can confirm your identity and your request, we will delete, de-identify, or aggregate your personal information so it can no longer be associated with you.  There are some reasons that the law may require or permit us to keep your personal information, however.
Opt-Out (Do Not Sell)
If you do not want us to disclose or transfer your personal information to a third party in exchange for something valuable, you may opt out by visiting privacy@drphil.com or calling 800.549.7529. When you call our toll free number, you will need to leave a name and address or email address that we can use to contact you.
Authorized Agents
If you are an authorized agent, you must make your request by emailing us at privacy@drphil.com
and put the words “CCPA Requests, Authorized Agents” in the subject field. You also need to attach to your email proof that you are registered with the Attorney General, as required by law, and proof you have written authority to act for the consumer.  You shall also provide the email address of the consumer you are representing so we can verify their identity, or provide documentation that you have power of attorney for the consumer pursuant to Probate Code sections 4000-4465.  We will not be able to honor requests without sufficient documentation that you are authorized to represent the consumer.
Requests made on behalf of a “Household”
If you would like to request personal information about your household, you may make your request by emailing us at privacy@drphil.com and putting the words "CCPA Household Request” in the subject field of the email. We will need to verify the members of the household, and in some cases, if a request raises security concerns for any household member, we may not be able to honor the request.
Financial Incentives
We do not offer any financial incentives for consumers to take any action or make any choices in using our services.
Non-Discrimination
We will not discriminate against you for exercising any of the rights described in this Privacy Policy. Specifically, we will not deny you goods or services or charge you different prices or rates for goods or services, including through the use of discounts or other benefits, or by imposing penalties.
California “Shine the Light” Law
Residents of the State of California may request a list of all third parties to which we have disclosed certain information during the preceding year for those third parties' direct marketing purposes.
California “Eraser” Law
If you are a California resident under the age of 18, and a user of the website where this policy is posted, you may request removal of content or information you have publicly posted. Please be aware that such a request does not ensure complete removal from the Internet of the content or information you posted, and there may be circumstances in which the law does not require or allow removal.
Exercising these Rights
For all requests under the “Shine the Light” or “Eraser” Law, you must put the words "Your California Privacy Rights Shine the Light/Eraser Law" in the subject field of an email to privacy@drphil.com, and include the name of the CBS Branded Service for which you are requesting the information. You must also include your full name, street address, city, state, and zip code. We will accept requests to exercise these rights only by email with the proper subject line and complete and accurate information.
Return to Top
CANADIAN RESIDENTS
This Privacy Policy complies with the requirements of the Personal Information Protection and Electronic Documents Act (PIPEDA). Under Canadian law, you have a right to access any personal information we hold about you. You may ask us to access and/or correct your information by emailing us at drphil-legal@drphil.com or writing to us at Peteski Productions, LLC, Attn: Legal, 2450 Colorado Avenue, Suite #500E, Santa Monica, CA 90404-3443. Please note that we may require you to send us proof of your identity before providing you with access to your personal information. If you send us a request to access or correct information, then we will contact you within 30 days (although it may take us longer to fully respond to your request). If you are not satisfied with our response to your query or complaint, you may also contact the Privacy Commissioner of Canada.
As our privacy policy makes clear, we may share information with third parties, such as co-branded partners and authorized third parties. However, we will only share your information with such parties where we have your express or implied consent to do so. If you object to our sharing your information with such parties, or if you do not wish to receive marketing communications (such as emails) from us, then you may contact us to let us know your objection at any time.
Return to Top
Membership
Effective Date: January 6, 2014
This Privacy Policy applies only to drphil.com (however accessed and/or used, whether via personal computers, mobile devices, or otherwise), which is owned or controlled by Peteski Productions, Inc. ("Company," "we," "our" or "us") or other interactive features that are accessible or downloadable through drphil.com and that post a link to this Privacy Policy (collectively, the "Web Site"). This Privacy Policy only covers information collected at the Web Site, and does not cover any information collected at any other web site or offline by Company (unless specifically stated). The purpose of this Privacy Policy is to disclose to you what information we may collect on the Web Sites, how we may collect it, with whom we may share it, and certain other matters related to such information, including the choices you may have regarding our collection, use, and disclosure of such information.
Please read this Privacy Policy carefully. In addition, please review our Terms of Use and Submission Guidelines, which govern your use of the Web Site and the content you submit to the Web Site, respectively.
TABLE OF CONTENTSTypes Of Information That May Be CollectedWeb Site Usage Information & Device IdentifiersInformation You Provide UsInformation From Other SourcesSend To A FriendHow Information May Be CollectedCookiesDo Not TrackWeb BeaconsHow We Use The Information CollectedThird-Party Ad Serving & Audience and Traffic Measurement ServicesWith Whom Information May Be SharedThird Parties Providing Services on Our BehalfWhen You Agree to Receive Offers From Third PartiesSweepstakes, Contest & PromotionsBusiness TransfersLegal Protection and Law EnforcementCorrecting/Updating Personal InformationChat Rooms, Forums, And Message BoardsThird Party Content and Links To Other Web SitesConsent To TransferSecurityA Special Note For Parents Concerning PrivacyNotification Of Changes And Your Acceptance Of The Privacy Policy Return to Top TYPES OF INFORMATION THAT MAY BE COLLECTED
The following are the types of information we may collect:
Web Site Usage Information & Device Identifiers
We may receive and store certain types of web site usage information whenever you visit or interact with the Web Site. For example, we may collect the page served, the time, the source of the request, the type of browser making the request, the preceding page view and other similar information. We may also collect your IP address or some other unique identifier for the particular device you use to access the Internet, as applicable (collectively referred to herein as a "Device Identifier"). A Device Identifier is a number that is automatically assigned to your computer, your cell phone, or other device used to access the Internet, and our computers identify your device by its Device Identifier. We may associate your Device Identifier with the personal information you provide. When analyzed, web site usage information helps us determine how visitors arrive at the Web Site, what type of content is most popular, what type of content you may find most relevant and what type of visitors are interested in particular kinds of content and advertising.
Information You Provide Us
A. We may receive information about you from other sources; for example, we may obtain geographic or demographic information, or information regarding your possible interests, from third parties, or we may receive information from a marketing partner in connection with a co-branded web site or promotion. We may use this information for a variety of purposes, including to enhance our ability to serve you and to tailor content and ads we serve to you. We may combine the information we receive from those other sources with information we collect through the Web Site. In those cases, we will apply this Privacy Policy to any personal information received, unless otherwise specifically disclosed by us at the time you provide your personal information
Information from Other Sources
We may ask you to provide us with two types of information: (1) personal information, which is information that could reasonably be used to identify you personally, such as your name, e-mail address, cell phone number and physical address; and (2) demographic information, such as gender, zip code, information regarding your education or number of children, or similar information. We may collect this information at various places and forms on the Web Site, including registration forms for newsletters and other communications (e.g., whether by e-mail, mobile device, etc.); when you communicate or otherwise interact with us, when you request show tickets; when you submit information to us (whether or not the information is intended to be posted on the Web Site); when you enter or participate in contests or sweepstakes, surveys or voting; or when you purchase a product or service through the Web Site. You may also be asked to choose a user name and password in order to identify yourself during future visits to the Web Site. Do not use your real name or the name of any other actual person as your user name. Providing us with information about yourself is your choice, and you can always choose not to provide certain information, but then you may not be able to take advantage of some of the Web Site's features.
Send To A Friend
If you send a friend a communication from the Web Site, the information you provide (names, e-mail addresses, phone numbers, etc.) is used on a one-time basis to facilitate the communication and is not used for any other marketing purpose, unless we obtain additional consent.
Return to Top HOW INFORMATION MAY BE COLLECTED (including Do Not Track)
Cookies
The Web Site uses standard technology called "cookies," which are small data files that are transferred to your computer (or other Internet-accessing device) when you visit the Web Site and allow your browser to accept cookies. Cookies automatically identify your web browser to the Web Site whenever you visit the Web Site, and may make navigating and using the Web Site easier for you. Also, by tracking how and when you use the Web Site, cookies help us determine which areas are popular and which are not. Many improvements and updates to the Web Site are based on data obtained from cookies. Additionally, accepting cookies may allow you to, among other things, personalize your experience on the Web Site. Cookies may also allow the Web Site to present to you advertising that may be of interest to you as well as limit how often you see certain ads that may detract from your user experience on our Web Site. If you do not want to allow information to be collected through the use of cookies, you can generally opt out of providing this information by setting your browser to reject cookies. However, please be aware that some areas of the Web Site may not provide you with an acceptable user experience if you have disabled the use of cookies.
Do Not Track
Some Internet browsers include the ability to transmit “Do Not Track” signals. Since uniform standards for “Do Not Track” signals have not been adopted, this Web Site does not process or respond to “Do Not Track” signals. To learn more about “Do Not Track”, please visit “All About Do Not Track” at http://www.allaboutdnt.com/.
Web Beacons
The Web Site and any communications sent by the Web Site may contain electronic images (generally, single-pixel ".gif" images) called "web beacons." These web beacons allow Company and third parties to monitor and collect certain information about the viewer of the web page, web-based document, e-mail message, or other communication, such as the type of browser requesting the web beacon, the Device Identifier of the device that the web beacon is sent to and the time the web beacon was viewed. Company's use of web beacons on its Web Site, include, without limitation, the following:
counting unique users (actually, unique web browsers), visits and page views.
monitoring traffic and conversion patterns through our various product and service offerings on the Web Site. For example, web beacons may be integrated into a merchandise product page as well as the subsequent shopping cart, transaction and verification pages.
personalizing your experience when you visit the Web Site, including the advertising and content you see.
determining whether or not messages were opened, links were clicked or notifications/offers were acted upon.
Return to Top HOW WE USE THE INFORMATION COLLECTED
The information you provide to us may be used to:
Send you newsletters and/or other communications for which you have registered;
Contact you about the Web Site, including, without limitation, in our discretion to notify you of changes to this Privacy Policy, the Web Site's Terms of Use, or other policies that affect your use of the Web Site;
Confirm or fulfill an order you have made;
Provide special offers or promotional materials to you on behalf of us or third parties;
Contact you with regard to a sweepstakes, contest or promotion in which you have participated;
Authorize a purchase or complete a transaction that you have requested, i.e., to deliver the products or other services that you ordered, and, if necessary, to invoice you;
Monitor or improve the Web Site;
Administer the Web Site's systems and for other internal business purposes;
Customize the advertising and content you see;
Comply with and monitor compliance with our Terms of Use and other applicable agreements and polices;
Evaluate you for a possible invitation to be a guest on the Dr. Phil Show;
Generate topics for the Dr. Phil Show;
Determine whether we may offer you a reservation to be a guest on the Dr. Phil Show; and
For other purposes disclosed when you provide your information.
Moreover, if you submit to Company and/or the Web Site comments, photographs, videos (including web cam videos), music, text or other content, it maybe published online or offline (including on-air, on a CD or DVD, through wireless distribution, and transmission of soft copies, or any other media or format currently existing or hereafter developed), and we may publish your name, voice, likeness and other personal information in connection with publishing the content or a portion of the content, and we may use the content and any excerpt from the content in connection with advertising, marketing, publicity and promotional activities. Please also see "Information You Submit" in our Terms of Use, which govern any content you submit through the Web Site and the content you submit to the Web Site, respectively.
Please note that information submitted to the Web Site via a "Ask Dr. Phil," "Send Your Comments" or other similar mechanisms will not necessarily receive a response. We will not use any such information you provide for marketing purposes unrelated to your request, although we may contact you regarding your submission or be a guest on the Dr. Phil Show.
Return to Top THIRD-PARTY AD SERVING & AUDIENCE AND TRAFFIC MEASUREMENT SERVICES
The Web Site may use third party network advertisers to serve advertisements on the Web Site and may use a traffic measurement service to analyze traffic on the Web Site. These third parties include advertisers, advertising agencies, and ad networks that may collect information about you when you view or interact with one of their advertisements and may collect information about your online activities over time and across different Web sites. Third parties may serve, track and/or analyze ads on our Web Site, and thereby may collect information about your online activities. Third-party ad serving enables us to target advertisements to you for products and services in which you might be interested.
Although advertisers and other companies do not have access to cookies set by the Web Site, the Web Site's third party ad network providers, the advertisers, the sponsors, and/or traffic measurement services may themselves set and access their own cookies on your computer if you choose to have cookies enabled in your browser or they may otherwise have access to non-personal information. These third party cookies are set to, among other things, help deliver advertisements to you that you might be interested in, to prevent you from seeing the same advertisements too many times and to conduct research regarding the usefulness of certain advertisements to you. Note that any images (or any other parts of a web page) served by third parties in association with third party cookies may serve as web beacons, which enable third parties to carry out the previously described activities. Third party cookies and web beacons are governed by each third party's specific privacy policy, not this one.
Some of these companies are members of the Network Advertising Initiative ("NAI"), which offers a single location to opt out of receiving tailored ads from member companies. To opt out of information collection by NAI member companies, or to obtain information about the technologies they use or their own privacy policies, please visit the NAI consumer opt out page.
Also, through the Digital Advertising Alliance ("DAA"), several media and marketing associations have developed an industry self-regulatory program to give consumers a better understanding of and greater control over ads that are customized based on their online behavior across different Web Sites. To learn more and make choices about interest-based ads from participating third parties, please visit the DAA consumer opt out page.
Return to Top WITH WHOM INFORMATION MAY BE SHARED
We do not share your personal information with third parties for those third parties’ marketing purposes unless you opt-in to such sharing at the time you provide your personal information. We may share non-personal information, such as aggregate user statistics, demographic information, and web site usage information with third parties. In addition, we may share your information as disclosed at the time you provide your information, as set forth in this Privacy Policy and in the following circumstances:
Third parties providing services on our behalf
We employ third parties to perform functions on our behalf; examples include hosting or operating the Web Site, sending e-mail and/or other communications, providing wireless services, removing repetitive information from customer lists, data analysis, marketing assistance, and customer service. These third parties may have access to your personal information for the purpose of performing such functions on the Web Site's behalf.
When You Agree To Receive Information From Third Parties
You may be presented with an opportunity to receive information and/or marketing offers from third party(s). If you do not agree to have your personal information shared, your personal information will not be shared with such third party(s) for direct marketing purposes. If you do agree to have your personal information shared, your personal information will be disclosed to such third party(s) and all information you disclose will be subject to the privacy policy and practices of such third party(s). We are not responsible for the privacy policies and practices of such third party(s) and, therefore, you should review the privacy policies and practices of such third party(s) prior to agreeing to receive such information from third party(s). If you later decide that you no longer want to receive communication from a third party, you will need to contact that third party directly
Sweepstakes, Contests and Promotions
We may offer sweepstakes, contests, and other promotions through the Web Site that may require registration. If you choose to enter a sweepstakes, contest or other promotion, your personal information may be disclosed to third parties in connection with the administration of such promotion, including, without limitation, in connection with winner selection, prize fulfillment, and as required by law, such as on a winners list. Also, by entering a promotion, you are agreeing to the official rules that govern that promotion, which may contain specific requirements of you, including, except where prohibited by law, allowing the sponsor(s) of the promotion to use your name, voice and/or likeness in advertising or marketing associated with the promotion.
Business Transfers
Company shares the information collected through the Web Site with and among its parent, subsidiaries and affiliates. Company or any of it assets, including the Web Site, may be sold, or other transactions may occur in which your personal information is one of the key business assets for the transaction. In such a case, your personal information may be one of the business assets we transfer. Hence, Company reserves the right to disclose and transfer user information, including personal information, in connection with a corporate merger, consolidation, restructuring, the sale of substantially all of our assets, or other corporate change.
Legal Protections and Law Enforcement
We may disclose information about our users, including your personal information, in the event we are required to respond to subpoenas, court orders, legal process or other valid law enforcement measures; to comply with a legal obligation; at the request of governmental authorities conducting an investigation; to verify or enforce compliance with the policies governing the Web Site and applicable laws; or to protect the legal rights, interests, or safety of the Web Site, our users or others. We may also use Device Identifiers to identify users, and may do so in cooperation with copyright owners, internet service providers, wireless service providers or law enforcement agencies in our discretion. Such disclosures may be carried out without notice to you.
Return to Top CORRECTING/UPDATING PERSONAL INFORMATION
The Web Site may contain web pages through which you can correct or update some of the personal information you have provided to us through registration with the Web Site. With regard to subscriptions, you also may cancel (or modify, if applicable) your subscriptions by following the instructions provided to you in applicable communications regarding such subscriptions.
Return to Top CHAT ROOMS, FORUMS, AND MESSAGE BOARDS
The Web Site may make chat rooms, forums, message boards, and user blogs available to its users. If you post personal information online, it will generally be publicly available and you may receive unsolicited messages from other parties. We cannot ensure the security of any information you choose to make public in a chat room, forum, message board, or blog. Also, we cannot ensure that parties who have access to such publicly available information will respect your privacy. Please exercise caution when disclosing personal information in these areas. Your use of chat rooms, forums, message boards and blogs is subject to our Terms of Use and Submission Guidelines
Return to Top THIRD PARTY CONTENT AND LINKS TO OTHER WEB SITES
When you are on the Web Site you may be directed to other sites that are operated and controlled by third parties that are beyond our control. For example, if you "click" on a banner advertisement, the "click" may take you off the Web Site onto a different web site. This includes links from advertisers, sponsors and partners that may use the Web Site's logo as part of a co-branding agreement. These other web sites may send their own cookies to you, independently collect data or solicit personal information and may or may not have their own published privacy policies. If you visit a web site that is linked from our Web Site, you should consult that web site's privacy policy before providing any personal information.
Return to Top CONSENT TO TRANSFER
The Web Site is operated in the United States. If you are located in the European Union, Canada or elsewhere outside of the United States, please be aware that any information you provide to us will be transferred to the United States. By using the Web Site or providing us with your information, you consent to this transfer.
Return to Top SECURITY
Company incorporates reasonable safeguards to help protect and secure your personal information. However, no data transmission over the Internet, or wireless transmission, or electronic storage of information can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. Please note that Company cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to Company via its Web Site, and you do so at your own risk.
Return to Top A SPECIAL NOTE FOR PARENTS CONCERNING PRIVACY
The Web Site is a general audience web site. We do not knowingly collect any personal information from children younger than the age of eighteen (18) on the Web Site and we will delete any information later determined to be from a user younger than eighteen (18).
Return to Top NOTIFICATION OF CHANGES AND YOUR ACCEPTANCE OF THE PRIVACY POLICY
By using the Web Site, you acknowledge your agreement to the terms of this Privacy Policy. From time to time, Company may update this Privacy Policy. However, Company will use your personal information in a manner consistent with the Privacy Policy in effect at the time you submitted the information, unless you consent to the new or revised policy.
